If you assembled a group of people and asked them to describe a "portable cassette player,"
如果你问很多人便携式磁带播放器是啥的话
it's more than likely they'd tell you about a Walkman or a boombox.
他们大多会说出索尼大法的随身听或者是八九十年代流行的手提音响
However, if you asked the same group to describe a "high end cassette recorder,"
然而，如果你问他们高级磁带录音机是什么的话
they'd probably tell you about a hi-fi component.
他们大多会跟你讲很多的Hifi设备
However, there is one type of cassette recorder that's both those things.
然而，有一种磁带录音机是两者兼备的
It's high end and it's portable, and, no surprise,
又高端又很便捷，当然啦
I've got one here today to show you,
我搞来了一个，现在给大家展示的是
this is the Sony TC-D5.
索尼的 TC-D5
Let's take a look at it.
咱们来仔细看看
Now, the Sony TC-D5 isn't just one cassette model, it's a total of four.
当然，索尼的TC-D5不只是只有这一个型号，实际上有四个
The version I've got here is the Pro II. This is the last revision.
我搞来的是Pro II，这个系列的最新型号
However, the original one that came out in 1978 was just called the TC-D5.
然而，初版机器是在1978年问世的，当时叫做TC-D5
That was revised in 1980 to the TC-D5M, which meant it could record onto metal tapes.
在1980年，改进型号TC-D5M问世，这个可以将声音录进金属磁带
注：相当于二类带（CrO2）和四类带
That one carried on being sold until 2005 approximately,
那个型号大概一直卖到2005年
but it forked in 1982. There was a Pro model issued which had XLR microphone inputs,
但是1982年，又分出个新型号。新的Pro型号可以输入XLR麦克风信号
and that was revised in 1986 and carried on to some time around about 1999, or maybe a little bit beyond there.
Pro型号在1986改进了，然后一直卖到1999年，也许更迟
So putting aside the more technical differences for the moment,
所以现在咱先不深入讨论他们之间的技术差异吧
things like different record heads and microphone amplification circuitry, things like that,
诸如不同的放大录音头或不同的麦克风放大线圈之类
your average chap industry is more interested in the fact that your
你们也许更加关心的是
"Pro" and "Pro II" only have XLR mic level inputs,
"Pro"和"Pro II"型号只有XLR信号输入接口
whereas the "prosumer" versions, the original and the M, have line level RCA inputs.
而面向普通消费者的呢，原版和"M"版本有RCA端口输入
And, outputs of course.
当然，输出也是一样
Let's just take a step back for the moment and talk about field recorders in general
现在，让我们先停下脚步，咱先来谈谈户外录音机到底是啥
because they are still in use.
因为他们现在仍在使用
Of course, nowadays people tend to use digital ones,
当然，现在人们更倾向用数字录音版的
some of these microphones will be for radio stations,
有一些麦克风是用在广播站的
they don't need to record video, so they just record onto a digital recorder.
他们不需要录像，将声音录在数码录音机上就OK了
And the same would have gone for back in the eighties.
在上世纪80年代，这个道理也是适用的
People would have been using cassette recorders for that purpose.
而人们更希望使用磁带录音机来完成这个目标
It was perfectly acceptable to use them for radio broadcasts. The quality was good enough for that.
对于广播来说，这就够用了，录音效果也还行
Of course, before then, people used reel-to-reel recorders and field recorders have existed
当然，在这之前，人们用过开盘机来录音
pretty much as long as recording itself has.
而户外录音机的历史正如录音技术的一样长
Of course, back in the sixties and seventies, when the TV news quite often relied on 16 mm film,
咱再回到六七十年代，当时电视经常使用16mm胶卷来录像
you'd have a separate sound chap recording the audio separate to the camera.
你得单独接个录音机录音，并将其接入摄像机
But of course, later on, we started synchronizing the video and the sound onto one device,
当然，在这之后，我们就将录音和录像功能给集合在一个机器上了
so field recorders tended to be used more just for radio.
那么户外录音机就更多地用在广播方面了
It wasn't that long ago that I was interviewed in the street like this.
不久之前我在街上就被这样采访
...I mean, not dressed up like a woman, like the comedian Dick Emery,
当然，不是这样的女装啊，像喜剧演员Dick Emery那样
but no, with a reporter coming up to me with a microphone in one hand,
只是记者一只手拿着麦克
cassette recorder slung over their shoulder.
另一个肩膀上跨着一个磁带录音机
That was for something on local radio news.
这个应该是给本地新闻用的
At the time the D5 came out, many of the rivals were only capable of recording in mono.
当TC-D5问世的时候，当时大多的同类产品只能录单声道
The D5 was capable of good quality stereo recording,
而TC-D5能录制相当不错的双声道录音
and therefore often put to good use in the tapers' section at a Grateful Dead concert.
因此这些设备都被用来录制Grateful Dead演唱会
And another early adopter of the D5 was Sony co-founder Masaru Ibuka,
还有一个人天天带着TC-D5，他就是索尼创始人井深大
who took one along with him on his business trips
他在出差的时候一直带着它
with a set of headphones to listen to classical music.
戴上耳机，听古典音乐
It had a good, long battery life but it was a little bit bulky,
这台机器续航能力强，但是比较笨重
and he mentioned this in early 1979 to Akio Morita, who was the chairman,
他在1979年的早期向盛田昭夫，当时索尼的主席，提起了这个东西
and that resulted in Sony developing their first Walkman.
然后索尼就开发出了最早的Walkman了
So just think, if the D5 hadn't existed,
所以好好想想吧，如果TC-D5没有存在过的话
perhaps the Walkman would never have happened.
也许Walkman就不会被发明出来
Sony called the TC-D5 the "ultimate portable cassette deck,"
索尼将TC-D5称作是“高级的便携式卡座”
and kept using that tagline throughout its life, and it was a long life as well.
并且一直带着这个名声卖这个，这个产品的销售周期也是相当地长
Looking back through the old Sony catalogs, you can see the D5 there in the 1980's and the 1990's.
看下以前的索尼产品目录，你会发现D5从八十年代到九十年代都有一席之地
All the other products in the catalog completely changed during that time,
别的产品来来去去，但是他永远在那里
@President Putin
whereas the D5 remains constant throughout.
TC-D5一直都在目录上
If it was a car, it would be like the Land Rover.
如果这是辆车的话，那一定是这辆路虎了
It looked very similar to the models that came out decades before,
这辆车看上去跟几十年前的车十分相似
but there was no need to change it because they got it right first time.
但是你不需要几年一换车，因为你上来就选对车了
And the same could be said for the D5.
对于TC-D5也是一样的吧
But when it comes to the, normally, fast-moving world of consumer electronics,
但是对于通常来说的，快速变化的消费级电子产品的话
the D5 is a bit of an anomaly.
这个东西就有点特立独行了
注：相当于AC-DC，无论时代如何发展，永远都是三和弦走天下
When it was first launched in 1978 when the BBC were using reel-to-reel recorders for their field work,
当这个于1978年发售的时候，BBC还在用开盘机来做户外录音
and then it existed throughout the years of the Walkman and the small dictaphones
然后这个一直度过了Walkman和小型数码录音机存在的年代
and carried on throughout,
然后一直继续发光发热
all the way through into the 21st century.
一路步入二十一世纪
I've even found it mentioned in this B&H catalog
我甚至在B&H产品目录上找到了这个
where you can find professional MiniDisc recorders,
那上面还有MiniDisc录音机啊
DAT recorders, CD-Rs, hard drives; but alongside all those,
数字磁带录音机啊，可刻录光盘啊，硬盘啊；但除了这些以外
it's still there, the D5 Pro II.
D5 Pro II 仍然在那里
Now, the reason I chose the Pro II over the other models in the range is because it was the last revision.
之所以我在那么多的型号中选择了Pro II型号，是因为这个是最终的版本
It actually came out in 1986.
实际上它是在1986年出售的
The D5M was last revised in 1980.
D5M型号则至少是在1980年出现的
The Pro II has a couple of improvements, such as the recording circuitry, better quality heads,
Pro II 型号有很多的提升，诸如循环录音，续航更持久
a shield over the heads to stop interference from buzzing, things like that.
还有磁头上面的护套，防止噪音干扰，还有很多
But the Pro models were only generally available through specialist outlets like B&H.
但是Pro型号基本只能通过特别的产品目录，诸如B&H，来购买
If you go on the Sony website, they still do "pro" products,
如果你去上索尼的官网，他们他们仍然在做“专业级”产品
you've got to go past the normal "consumer" stuff, down to the bottom here you can see the pro range,
你必须跳过平常的“消费级”产品介绍，一路到底才能看见专业级产品
and the stuff there is really for broadcasters.
这些产品才是真正为了广播级别的
And if you have a look at some of the prices on this, you can see why they classed it as pro.
如果你看一下价格的话，你就知道为什么他们是专业级产品了
For example, this point-of-view camera is $75,000.
比如这个视点镜头相机要价75000美元（约合49万元）
So yeah, you can see this "pro" cassette recorder is designed for that market, and it feels quality as well.
那你就会发现这个“专业级磁带录音机”是为消费市场设计的，而且质量很好
The whole thing is made out of metal. There's a couple of bits of plastic here and there,
整个外壳是金属的，仅有几块塑料在这儿
but really, the whole body and the structure of the thing is just solid.
但整体来说，整个机器的做工十分地紧实
It's designed to take a kick and keep on recording.
它被设计为按一下就能持续录音
Along the bottom here, you can see this section is made out of a rubber,
再看这个底部，你可以看到这个地方是由橡胶做的
and that's a kind of protective bumper because when you hold it on your side,
类似于保护套之类的，因为当你将其挂在你身上时
if you were to drop it, that's the part it would land on.
要是drop it的话，那一端会先落地
Even the battery compartment has a metal cover.
甚至电池仓都有一个金属盖
Might not sound like a big deal, but very rare to see that.
听上去没啥，但是很少见
The batteries inside here are two standard "D" cells,
电池仓里面是两个一号电池
which will power it for approximately 4 and 1/2 to 5 hours.
大约能续航四个半到五个小时
There are, of course, advantages to using off-the-shelf batteries like these
当然，用这种外置电池是有好处的
as opposed to having a rechargeable device,
而不是使用内置电池的可充电设计
especially if you've got your field recorder in the middle of nowhere,
尤其是当你在户外录音到半截
somewhere where there's no power. How would you recharge anything?
录音机没电了，你怎么充电呢？
You could always carry along a few extra batteries with you, though.
然而你可以身上多带几块电池
And also I noticed in this article it was about recording audio for the radio.
我还看见有记载说用这个录制广播里的音乐
They mentioned that after the tsunami, the only machine that was still working was the D5
他们还说在海啸过后，只有TC-D5能正常工作
when their more modern MiniDisc and DAT machines had already given up.
而那些更加现代化的MiniDisc录音机或数字磁带录音机全部罢工
I should also mention that both my Pro II model and the D5M can be run off DC power.
还有，Pro II型号和D5M型号可以接普通的直流电电源
However, I don't think the same goes for the original Pro.
然而，我觉得原版的Pro型号不能接
Where mine's got a DC power jack, that's got a stereo and mono switch.
我的上面本应该是直流电接口的地方，却是双声道和单声道转换按钮
Right, so I want to show you something now.
好的，现在我要给大家展示了
I've taken the Pro II outside, I've got something recorded on this cassette.
我把录音机拿到户外，磁带上也录有东西
I'm going to play it into the camera and, just have a listen to this for a moment.
我将播放磁带，并内录进摄像机。请大家欣赏
[Playback]: "If you want to develop a professional field recorder,
如果你想要开发一个专业级的户外录音机
you can't just take a typical cassette mechanism
你不能把平常的机械结构直接应用在上面
and plonk it into a case along with some batteries.
随便塞进个外壳，再放块电池
No, because as soon as you were to move it,
这是绝对不行的，因为当你移动录音机的时候
the sound would become wobbly.
声音就会失真
This is due to variations in the tape speed.
这是磁带转速的不同所导致的
It's something more commonly referred to as "wow" and "flutter."
一般大家将这种声音称作"哇~"或者"扑通"
Shaking the D5 though has no effect. The playback speed is unaltered,
然而鬼畜摇晃这个录音机却没有失真，播放速度依旧平稳
and this is thanks to a new type of drive mechanism that Sony developed
这都是索尼专门为这台机器开发的全新机械机构
just for this machine.
所发挥的作用
This kind of performance was vital for a device that has to record broadcast-quality audio
这样的效果对于录制广播级别的高品质录音来说十分重要
whether it's at a press conference sat on a table,
无论是在相对平静的新闻发布会中
or slung over the shoulder of a reporter running through a war zone.
还是在战地中，记者跨着它进行采访
Now that really was quite impressive!
这个小玩意确实很耐人！
Of course nowadays though, when people are listening to solid state devices
当然，现在的人们都在使用“固态设备”欣赏音乐
with no moving parts, it doesn't quite have the same impact.
没有可动的机械结构，自然也没有那么多失真
But when this thing came out, that was a bit of a revelation.
可当年这个发售的时候，确是革命性的
It's all down to this very clever motor mechanism, which I can't even begin to explain to you
一切都要归功于这个精巧的电机设计，精巧到我都解释不了
because I don't quite understand it myself.
因为我对此不甚了解
But it's kind of a direct drive kind of thing. You've got a wheel, you've got another thing
但应该是某种直连电机之类的吧，齿轮
注：一般的磁带机或复读机都是由橡胶环来连接马达和转动机构的
that's attached to the wheel, which drives it in a certain way that doesn't get affected by
卡着齿轮，只顺着一个路子驱动，进而减少了
译者淘气：这是一个组装图，由正视图和俯视图构成
movement or gravity or things.
移动和重力的影响
All very clever, and later on employed in the Sony D6C Professional Walkman as well,
确是精妙，后来 Sony D6C 专业级 Walkman 也使用了这个设计
but I can't really demonstrate it or show you how it works, so let's just put the cover back on here.
但我现在确实是无法演示这个的工作原理，所以咱还是注意其他的方面吧
But I will show you around the machine itself.
但是我还是会给大家展示这个机器的方方面面
If we start off on the left hand side,
如果咱们从左手边的方向开始介绍的话
we can see we've got a little part that's sticking out of there,
我们可以清晰地看到有个小东西十分突出
and that's to attach a strap to so you can put it over a shoulder. There's one on the other side as well.
那个地方是系跨带的地方，另一侧也有一个
At the bottom corner we've got a 6.5 mm stereo headphone jack and above that there's a
在底下的一角有一个6.5mm的双声道话筒插口
control to adjust the volume of that,
上面有个控制音量的旋钮
which also affects the volume of the speaker on the top.
这个同时也控制上面的扬声器音量
It's just a mono speaker really designed just for listening back to what you've recorded
to check there's something there.
这个仅仅是一个单声道扬声器，仅仅为了回听你的录音，保证录上了东西
It's not a high quality speaker.
不是啥高级喇叭
The keys on this are the typical piano key design, which was popular in the 70's,
这个按键是十分基本的钢琴按键，上世纪70年代的流行设计
later on replaced by the kind of touch logic controls.
后来就是一触即可的设计了
This is basic, but it's basic because it worked and it doesn't go wrong.
这个按键十分普通，普通但是可靠
Over on the right hand side, we've got the twin VU meters for the left and right stereo
右手边的呢，是个VU表，表示左右声道音量大小
and a couple of other controls I'll show you a little bit later on.
还有一些其他按键，我一会提到的
There's no button to open the cassette door. However,
这台机器没有开仓键，但是呢
once you've opened it manually, you can see we've got a couple of additional lever switches in here,
当你手动掀开仓门后，你可以看到很多其他的水平开关
one of which turns Dolby B on or off, and the other one selects tape formulations,
一个是控制杜比B降噪功能的开关，一个是选择磁带类型的
between type I and type III.
是一类铁带还是三类铬铁带
You might remember type III being the shortly-lived formulation, that wasn't on the market all that long.
我之前提过，三类带是个短命的磁带类型，在市场存在时间较短
注：BV19W41187Dc 磁带:比你记忆中更优秀 @ Techmoan & xy1154
However, this also automatically identifies type II, which is chrome tape,
然而，这个还能自动侦测二类铬带
from this little lever at the back. It can play back metal tapes, but it can't record to them.
利用后面的这个小机构。它可以播放四类金属带，但是录不了
If you want to record to metal tapes, then you'll need the TC-D5M, the "M" standing for "metal."
如果你有录制铁带的需要，你得用TC-D5M型号,其中"M"即指金属(metal)
It's a bit unusual that the prosumer model can record to metal,
这就有点不同寻常了，消费级产品可以录四类金属带
whereas the professional model can't,
而专业级的就不行
and some people say that's perhaps because you need more power to record to metal,
有人解释为录制四类金属带可能更耗电
so the batteries can last a little bit longer,
所以没有这个功能，录音时间还能更长些
and it doesn't really matter anymore nowadays because it's very hard to find metal tapes,
不过现在无所谓了，因为四类金属带十分难找
and since you can play them back and record to chrome and ferric,
并且你都可以录制并播放二类铬带或是一类铁带
that's pretty much all you need in a deck nowadays.
这个估计就是你手上所有的磁带类型了
And then when it comes to playing back tapes,
现在咱来谈谈回放磁带
this diminutive little machine puts in an excellent performance whether it's tape type I, II, III, or IV.
这个微小的机械结构播放磁带的效果还挺好，无论是什么类型的磁带
As long as the original recording was done to a high standard, this thing will reproduce a sound,
只要播放的磁带的录制效果很好，这个东西回放磁带
the kind of which you don't even tend to get out of most home hi-fi decks.
效果很好，好到某些发烧级卡座都没有那么好
And it looks good while it's doing it. I'm a sucker for these bouncing VU needles.
而且机器播放时的效果还很好，我对VU表来回动十分厌恶
I'll also point out that the left hand one is a battery indicator.
我还需要指出的是左面的表是一个电池指示器
If you press this button, you can see the needle stays in position to show you
如果我按下那个按钮，你可以看到指针不动了
how much battery power you've got left in there.
而它指向的位置即为电量的剩余值
And it also turns on a little backlight, although it is quite dim, as you can see here, and it's only on momentarily.
而且这个还能开启一点背光，尽管暗到你看不到，而且只是亮一小会
Once you've used this machine for a while,
当你使用这个机器有一会的时候
you really start to get an appreciation for some of the finer details.
你就开始觉得这个机器的细节真的是走心了
Little basic things, like this eject button here.
一些十分基本的东西，诸如这里的弹出按钮
All it is is a simple lever that's designed to pop the cassette out of the machine,
还有一个小的杠杆，用来将磁带从机器里弹出来
but it's just such a simple little mechanism that works,
就是那么地小，但是工作得很好
why bother doing anything different?
都这么好了，你还想期待什么呢？
Now, of course, if you're playing back any music through this, you don't want to be doing it
当然，如果你想用这个播放音乐，你肯定不想用
through that built-in speaker, because it's just a tinny little speaker that's designed so that you can tell
内置扬声器，因为这个扬声器很小，仅仅是用来让你知道
that there's something on the tape.
磁带上到底录了什么
You really want to plug it into some sort of external amplifier
你必须要将其插入某种外置功放
or you could just plug those RCA plugs into external powered speakers like I've got here,
或者你可以通过RCA插口来插入外置音箱，像我这样
and it makes a heck of a difference.
效果确实有很大不同
One reason I used this machine when I was demonstrating the Atari Video Music the other week
我之所以上回用这个机器来演示Atari Video Music
is because you can have two live audio outputs at the same time,
是因为你可以有同时两个音频输出
so I could plug the RCA outputs into the Atari and the headphone output came out of the front
所以我可以通过RCA输出直到Atari那里，前面我再利用耳机输出
and into the camera that I was recording everything with.
插入相机，因为我把所有东西都录到相机里
Talking of recording, you've got a record level dial here,
说道录音，你可以看到这里有一个录音音量旋钮
made out of metal. It's sort of gunmetal, in a way.
金属做的，还是暗灰色的
The whole thing feels a little bit military at times. It's just so well put together.
整个东西摸上去很有质感，整合得真不错
But, as you can see, you can adjust the left and right separately,
但是，如你所见，你可以分别调整左右两个声道
and of course, during interviews, they might have had one microphone for one person,
当然，在采访的时候，他们兴许一个人一个麦克风
one for the other and you could have adjusted the levels;
你可以调整两个麦克风的音量了
however, if you want to plug something into this,
然而，如果你想将什么东西插入到这俩大接口的话
you can get a lead which will convert RCA into microphone balanced XLR inputs;
你得搞条RCA端口至麦克风专用XLR接口的转接线
however, once you plug those into an output,
当你将这些插入之后
say, from a line out from a CD player, like I'm doing here, and then plug the other end into the D5,
诸如我这样，一端插入CD播放机，另一端插入TC-D5
you find that line level outputs are a lot "hotter," a lot louder than microphone level
你会发现信号输出有点“强”，比麦克风输出还要高
so that, if I put pause on here and pressed record,
所以，如果你就这样插，按下录音键的话
you can see that it's just peaking the whole thing out completely.
你可以看到音频信号一直非常强
We've got the peak light shining at the top there as well, next to the record light.
上面在“录制灯”旁边的“强度”灯，也是非常亮的
You can see, if I just turn it up slightly, it's just straight into the peaks.
你可以看到，我就稍微旋转了一下，VU表就直接最强了
So, the line level output needs to be brought down to the level of a mic level input.
所以说，线缆输出需要将麦克风输入电平降低一下
Fortunately, they've got this switch on the side here which takes 20 decibels off it,
幸好，这个旁边有个开关，可以将信号降低20分贝
so if we do that, we can bring it down to a level the device is supposed to record at.
所以我们那么做的话，我们可以将信号电平降低，就可以录了
Now, I'm not sure whether I'm supposed to be doing it this way, but it does seem to work fine
呃，虽然我不知道这样做好不好，但是这样也行
so I'm just going to carry on. But yeah. You've also got a limiter at the bottom right.
所以我就这样继续旋转。没错，右面底下也有一个限制音量开关
Notice if I turn this all the way up, we have it so it's peaking out,
我注意到如果我一路往上旋转这个，我们的信号就太强了
turn the limiter on, and it will try and keep it back within normal recording level parameters.
开启限制音量开关的话，机器就会尽量将信号电平放在一个合理的区间内
That's for if you're at some sort of loud concert,
这个在录制比较吵的音乐会
or somewhere where there's gonna be loud noises every now and then.
或者在噪音会很大的音乐会上会有点用
You want it just to limit those so doesn't oversaturate the recording.
你肯定想限制这些信号，这样就不会破音，或者音量过大了
You might have noticed that my machine is in really good condition.
你也注意到了，我的这台机器品相不错
In fact, the only marks on it are these little two scratches on the top here in the black paint.
实际上，这上面只有在黑漆这里有两处小小的抓痕
But that's it. And the reason that it's in such good condition
然后就没啦。这台机子品相好的原因在于
is because it was kept in its protective case.
我们有一个保护套
That's one of the great things about field recorders.
这个对于户外录音机来说，是相当不错的
They all came with one of these protective cases, so as long as the person who owned it before you
他们一般会附带保护套，所以只要之前的所有者
kept it in there, there's a good chance that it won't have got these scratches and marks
将机器放在里面，大概率机器上没有什么明显的爪痕和信号
that something of this age would usually have by now.
而这在现在的老机器上十分常见
As you can see, once you put it inside the case,
如你所见，只要将其放入保护套中
the original strap connectors go through holes in there,
机子上挂跨带的地方就能穿过保护套上的洞
and then your strap is supposed to attach to the connectors on the case itself.
然后跨带应该就可以挂在保护套上了
My case has got a few scratches and nicks in it. The leather's started to peel away in places,
我的保护套上有一些爪痕和污渍，有些地方的皮革开始脱位
but it's done its job. It's protected the machine.
但是它尽到了本分，保护了机器
In fact, you can even replace the cassettes inside the deck without taking it out of the case.
实际上，你可以不把机器从保护套里拿出来，就能换磁带
The only thing you'll need to take it out for, really, is to replace the batteries.
你需要拿出来的唯一情况，就是换电池
Now while Sony might have had the D5 on the market longer than any other rival model,
虽然索尼卖TC-D5的时长超过了其他的同类产品
there were quite a few other machines that came and went during its lifetime, from a number of different manufacturers.
但是其他厂家仍然在其售卖期间推出了一些竞争品
One of the more respected of those was Marantz, and this model here
其中一家为大众所知的是 Marantz，这个机器呢
does bear quite a striking resemblance to the D5 in places.
在某些地方确实与TC-D5非常相似
The model is the CP430, that's the European model number,
这个型号是CP430，在欧洲售卖的型号
in the US it was known as the PMD430.
在美国，它被称为PMD430
It does Dolby B, but it also does dbx.
它有Dolby B降噪功能，但也能进行dbx降噪
This is the only dbx machine I've got, I only picked this up a couple of weeks ago.
我手里只有这个机器，我几周前才买到手
It's quite high end. It does chrome and metal recording as well.
确实是专业级的，可以录制二类铬带和四类金属带
You can see down at the bottom here we've got a pitch and a bias control on there,
看底下，你可以看到有音高和左右平衡控制
and it's also a 3 head machine.
这个机器有三个磁头
So that means I can listen back to the recordings that it's making as it's making them.
也就是说，我可以边录音边监听
And you just press that button down there to listen to either the tape
你还可以按下底部的这个按钮来监听磁带
or the source.
或者是音乐
So when it comes to features, it appears that this device has the Sony beaten hands-down.
要说功能呢，这玩意可谓是甩了索尼的机器十万八千里了
However, when it comes to build quality, the Sony is clearly the victor.
但是机器质量呢，索尼显然更胜一筹
Where the Sony's got a solid metal construction,
索尼的机器是全金属设计
this has a flimsy, creaky plastic one.
而这个的外壳却是脆弱易碎的塑料:-(
The Sony feels like a metal brick,
索尼的机器拿在手里很有分量
this feels like an empty plastic box.
这玩意嘛，拿手里更像是空的塑料盒子
And after reading up a little bit online, it seems like the wow and flutter numbers
读带子读了一会后，好像放带子时的失真
aren't that impressive for this machine, either.
对于这个机器来说，还是很多的
Something else I'd learned while doing a bit of research for this video:
我在看这个视频研究的时候，我发现
You know, earlier on I mentioned the BBC used these Uher 4400 recorders.
我注意到BBC用的是这个Uher 4400录音机
I've even seen those for sale on eBay saying "ex-BBC" and they've got all the stamps and things on them.
我还看到eBay上面还有卖的，描述是"ex-BBC"，还有很多邮票之类的东西
Well, when they replaced those, they didn't use the D5.
好吧，当他们换下这个的时候，他们没有使用TC-D5
No, instead, they used its smaller newer brother the Sony D6C.
他们使用的更新到型号，索尼D6C
Which is classed as a professional Walkman,
一般被认为是更高端的Walkman
but really it's a very sophisticated little portable recorder,
但这个确实是一个复杂的小型便捷磁带录音机
able to record using Dolby C and record onto metal-- both things that I can't do with my D5.
可以用Dolby C降噪，可以录在四类铁带上，这两件事我的D5一个都干不了
But I will talk more about the D6C in a future video.
但也许我会在将来谈论这个 D6C 录音机吧
注：BV1s4411K7wZ Walkman 购买指南 @ Techmoan & 无幻无风
I plan on doing a video where I talk about the Walkman,
我计划要做期谈论Walkman的视频
and I'll feature it in that one, but getting back to the D5.
其中会包括这个，但咱还是来谈论TC-D5吧
I think it's time to do the wrap-up.
我想是时候总结一下了
There are still plenty of people out there that, for one reason or another, need a decent quality cassette deck.
现在仍然有很多人，由于各种原因，需要高质量的卡座
But if you go looking to buy a new one, nowadays, there's very little choice.
但是你要现在买的话，你的选择实际上很少
You've got your cheap, plasticky novelties, the things that convert tapes to MP3s,
你只能买那些便宜的塑料小玩意，可以将磁带转录成MP3
注：BV18V4112749 将磁带转录成MP3文件的超差方式 @ David Murray & HikariCalyx
and one of the things that people have asked me to review a lot is the elbow cassette player,
你们也有很多人想让我评测Elbow卡带播放器
but that's just a design concept at the moment.
但是现在这个只是个概念:-P
Pretend it's like a concept car at a motor show. You can't buy it,
假装这是个在车展上的概念车，你没法买啊
and whether or not anything like that will ever come to the market in the future?
这个东西将来能不能上市还是个问题呢
注：我上网搜索了一下，貌似还买不到:-P
We'll just have to wait and see on that one.
我们可能还要等待一段时间才会有吧
As far as things you can go in a real shop somewhere in the world and buy?
那么，现在还能在市面上买到什么呢？
Well, in the US, you can go get the Tascam CD-A580.
在美国的话，你可以买到 Tascam CD-A580
That costs $400 over there,
大约是400美元（大约2600元）多一点
and it doesn't have any kind of Dolby noise reduction circuitry
这个卡座也没有任何的杜比降噪技术支持
I'd imagine that's perhaps down to some sort of licensing issues.
我猜这是因为某些授权问题吧
My preference, though, would be to go for something older.
要我来说，我更乐意想找些老式的东西
But even if you go back to 1990, you're still talking 27 years old,
但就算回到1990年，那也是27年前啊
so you got to buy something that was top-quality back in the day if it's going to be working perfectly nowadays,
所以如果现在能用的话，你得买当时最高端的设备
and you won't get much better quality than one of these things.
并且你也买不到比这些更好的了
Now they quite often get overlooked when it comes to second-hand tape players
然而这些二手磁带机却常被忽视
because they don't look particularly impressive.
因为它们看起来没有那么吸引人
Once they're in the case it could be some sort of dictation machine or something.
当它们装在盒子的时候，你也许会认为这些是某种新冠病毒检验试剂啥的
And if you just search for "portable cassette recorder,"
如果你只是搜索“便携式磁带播放器”的话
you'll get a big list of rubbishy things popping up.
你会看到一大堆垃圾显现出来
You need to know the model numbers. So what I've done,
你必须得知道具体的型号，所以我就在
I put some model numbers in the video description of ones
视频描述中放了一些型号
that you could search for which might point you in the right direction.
你可以上网搜索它们，兴许会找到你所需要的吧
But hopefully you've enjoyed this video, and as always,
无论如何，希望大家喜欢这集，一如既往
thanks for watching.
感谢大家观看;-)
感谢以下在Patrons支持我的人！
Techmoan的Pateron地址为https://www.patreon.com/techmoan
片尾有彩蛋，先看一会Peter Sinfield的诗作吧
The Letters - Peter Sinfield
With quill and silver knife
She carved a poison pen
Wrote to her lover's wife:
"Your husband's seed has fed my flesh".
As if a leper's face
That tainted letter graced
The wife with choke-stone throat
Ran to the day with tear-blind eyes.
Impaled on nails of ice
And raked with emerald fire
The wife with soul of snow
With steady hands begins to write:
"I'm still, I need no life
To serve on boys and men
What's mine was yours is dead
I take my leave of mortal flesh"
根据 西贡祢豆子@zhihu 修改
以翎羽做底 刻刀雕琢
她削出一根砒霜之笔
写信给她情人的妻子
“你丈夫的种子已为我所养”
仿佛麻风病人的脸一样
信被染上败坏的光晖
那妻子冷硬的喉咙呜咽
直到双目被泪水洗瞎
被残酷的寒钉刺穿
又受艳绿火焰的炙烤
如白雪般纯洁的妻子
从容地执笔回复
我事已尽，无需再为
服侍老小，日夜辛劳
你的情人将永久地留在我的怀里
我也要抛下这终会腐朽的肉体了
Epitaph - Peter Sinfield
The wall on which the prophets wrote
Is cracking at the seams
Upon the instruments of death
The sunlight brightly gleams
When every man is torn apart
With nightmares and with dreams
Will no one lay the laurel wreath
When silence drowns the screams
Confusion will be my epitaph
As I crawl a cracked and broken path
If we make it we can all sit back and laugh
But I fear tomorrow I'll be crying
Yes I fear tomorrow I'll be crying
根据 西贡祢豆子@zhihu 修改
先知留下字迹的那面墙
缝隙逐渐裂开
被冤魂缠绕的兵械之上
日光灼灼闪烁
当每一个人
都被梦魇与理想撕裂
将无人献上月桂花环
若寂静淹没了喧嚣
“困惑”将是我的墓志铭
当我在残破的小径上彳亍前行
若我可豁然通达 我们便可通达并大笑
可是，我害怕明天的我将会哭泣
是的，我不想明天的我将会哭泣
Between the iron gates of fate
The seeds of time were sown
And watered by the deeds of those
Who know and who are known
Knowledge is a deadly friend
If no one sets the rules
The fate of all mankind I see
Is in the hands of fools
Confusion will be my epitaph
As I crawl a cracked and broken path
If we make it we can all sit back and laugh
But I fear tomorrow I'll be crying
Yes I fear tomorrow I'll be crying
在命运的铁门之间
时间的种子已经播下
并由智者名士的事迹浇灌
不知是谁 也不知由谁记住
当无人立下规则之时
知识是一位致命之友
我看见全人类的命运
皆掌握在愚者的手中
“困惑”将是我的墓志铭
当我在残破的小径上彳亍前行
若我可豁然通达 我们便可通达并大笑
可是，我害怕明天的我将会哭泣
是的，我不想明天的我将会哭泣
注意！
现在请不要播放这个视频，否则
“没有意思的，幼稚的并且愚蠢的”玩偶秀将会上演！
Ugh, tapes.
天哪，那堆该死的磁带
I was glad when those things died off! Good riddance.
老天爷啊！他们终于消失了！
Why do you keep watching videos about things that you don't like...and then complain about them?
那你为什么还要看那些是不喜欢的东西，然后再抱怨两句呢？
Because I need to let these idiots know that they're listening to music the wrong way!
因为我需要让那些听磁带的老掉牙们知道他们听歌的方式不对！
I don't understand why you feel threatened every time something does something different to you.
我真搞不懂，当有些东西违背你的常识时，你为何老想排斥呢？
I don't. I'm helping them out by informing them that there are better options.
我才没有，我只是向他们推荐更多的优质选项
Just like yesterday? When you saw that person riding a horse and you shouted, "get a car!"
像昨天那样？咱儿子买了张二手CD，你说：“你手机上听不就行了吗？"
Exactly! A car is better than a horse,
那当然！手机比CD更方便啊！
and streaming music is better than listening to a tape!
同理，流媒体音乐比听磁带更好！
Well, rather than complaining, instead why don't you make your own video
好吧，先少抱怨吧。你为何不做期视频
explaining how great streaming music is?
来说流媒体音乐到底有多好呢？
That's not a bad idea!
这主意不错:-)
Okay, let's pretend this is the video now. So, three, two, one, action!
好吧，假装咱现在是在拍视频。那么，三、二、一......开拍！
Oh, um.
好的，额......
Hey, what's up there Youtube?
B站的同志们，大家好啊！
Listen guys! In this video, I'm going to be telling all you cassette users
本期视频呢，我给你们这些磁带的忠实粉丝
about a new thing called streaming music!
介绍一个新的东西，叫流媒体音乐
Good, keep going.
挺好，继续
Oh, um
好的，那么......
Well, with streaming music, you can pick any record you like,
好的，当你用流媒体音乐时，你可以随意浏览专辑
listen back to the music,
在任何时候都可以
anytime you want...
听音乐......
Um, it's... It's music...
就是，就是音乐嘛......
It's... real-really good!
反正......反正很好就对了:-|
You suck!
介玩意太次了！
What?
嘛玩意？
I'm just playing the part of you! Carry on.
我在学你抱怨，好吗。继续
Alright, um.
好吧......
Streaming music is really cheap, and it doesn't get stuck in your machine,
流媒体音乐很便宜，而且不会缠带
just like every tape does, every time you play it.
就像你每次播放磁带时都要经历的一样
Boo! This is rubbish!
得了吧！流媒体差劲得要死！
Everyone knows about streaming,
所有人都知道流媒体音乐
and your nose sounds blocked! You're a moron! And this video stinks!
你是不是该擤鼻子了！你这个二胡货！这个视频也很差得一批！
Um, and if you stream,
呃......当你听流媒体音乐的时候
you'll be doing what everyone else does, so you'll be normal.
你和你周围的人没什么两样，你就显得合群了
And you won't have to store all those records and tapes and things.
你也没必要在家里腾地方放你收藏的唱片，磁带之类的了
So what if I already use streaming music, but I also collect records and tapes?
要是我已经使用流媒体音乐，但是我还要收藏唱片和磁带呢？
Uh...you need to stop doing what you enjoy, and do what I want you to do.
好吧，你就别收藏了，做你该做的事
And then I'll feel happier about the choices that I've made!
然后你就会觉得你的决定是多么明智啊！
Okay, wrap it up now!
好的，别说了！
Right, um. That's it you guys out there in Youtube land for this week!
好的，那么，感谢大家收看我的节目！
Don't forget to like and subscribe!
不要忘了点赞三连哦！
Thumbs down, unsubscribed, and... scene!
我要点踩，取关，还要...... 现在卡！
I thought that went really well!
我觉得刚才那样还行诶:-P
本视频由SuperBart翻译，原作者Techmoan发布于2017-05-09